- I'm onto you.
- You should have killed me
when you had the chance.
I'm drunk on power.
SHE LAUGHS
- There's a "Hug" in my name.
- But get too close.
there'll be a dagger in your back.
22 players arrived at
this Scottish castle.
hoping to win up to £120.000.
This game has
officially started.
One by one.
the Faithful have fallen.
"By order of the Traitors.
you have been murdered."
And with two Traitors
caught along the way...
Traitor!
CHEERING
A Traitor.
..now two Traitors
and four Faithful remain.
After an uphill battle
in the mission...
Go!
Come on. we need this!
..the Faithful were rewarded.
You have stopped the Traitors
committing their final murder!
At the penultimate Round Table...
James. last night's behaviour.
I haven't been able to look past it.
..suspicions intensified...
If you were a Traitor.
the possibility that you saw Fiona
and was like. "I don't want to work
with this person. Get her out now."
That's one of
my proudest achievements.
Don't take that away from me.
..but with the votes
reaching deadlock...
I'm sorry. James.
James and Rachel. the banishment
will be decided by chance.
..who will make it to the final
and be in with a chance
of taking home the prize?
This is The Traitors Final.
James and Rachel.
this is for a place in the final.
Whoever's chest contains a Shield.
you are saved from
tonight's banishment.
Please open the chest...
..in three...
..two...
..one.
Hey-ho!
Rachel. you have the Shield.
You are safe from banishment.
James. your chest did not
contain a Shield.
You have been banished.
Please come up here and join me.
James. you have been banished
from the castle.
Please reveal. are you a Faithful
or are you a Traitor?
It's been amazing.
I've learned a lot about myself.
And it's just been
an incredible experience.
I feel strangely serene right now.
What a game.
Thank you.
At the first Round Table.
when the blindfolds went on.
I was selected immediately -
and have been from the start -
as a trait-ful...
..Faithful.
GROANS
Good luck. everyone. Good luck.
Been a pleasure.
No. No. no. no. no. no!
Faithful. you have lost
one of your own
at such a late stage in the game.
However. the good news.
there is no murder.
Also. you are my finalists.
Congratulations.
Have a wonderful evening.
No.
That was horrible.
I knew I was going to come
under fire.
but to leave it to chance.
like. that was just unbelievable.
I really. really appreciated
Stephen's support tonight.
He had my back.
So. yeah. it didn't go unnoticed.
I appreciate you
listening to me. Jack.
if it doesn't mean much now.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
It was really kind of horrible.
Yeah. I can't imagine.
Like. the chance stuff is crazy.
- It's really frustrating the way
all this is playing out.
- Mmm.
I was going to enjoy
standing up there and telling you
that I'm a Faithful and kind of
rubbing it in people's faces.
But it just looks so bad that
it was me and him up
and then he says that. cos it's just
going to look directly at me.
And that's the way the whole thing
is constructed.
- It's not just you. Here.
- I shouldn't have changed mine.
He's just been himself
the whole time.
I just... I just wasn't convinced
by what he said.
I've taken James's chance away
of being in the final
and he was a Faithful.
and I feel terrible.
Cos he was my mate.
I shouldn't have changed my mind.
- This is an impossible game.
- It's so hard.
- How are we supposed to know?
I so almost put Rachel's name down
on that final vote.
If we got Rachel out tonight.
knowing how the room was feeling
about me in general.
I think it would have just
been easier for me
to get to the endgame by myself.
I really underestimated
how difficult this would be.
- All right?
- Yeah.
- Obviously. just shitting it.
- It's awful.
Yeah. I know.
What you said to me
out there as well
is sort of making me think
I did make a mistake today.
I know you've made a mistake.
This game is so frustrating.
Straight after the Round Table.
I felt as if
the way Rachel came across
did seem really Faithful.
She just said to me she was quite
looking forward to standing up there
and rubbing it in our faces
that she was a Faithful.
I resonate with that
because I'd feel the exact same
if I was to stand up there.
and I feel that leads me
towards Stephen and Jade.
Jack. it mightn't mean an awful lot
now. but I appreciate your vote.
How are you feeling?
Obviously it's just
very carefully manipulated around
to make it look like me. because if
I was a Faithful. I would murder me.
Or if I was a Traitor.
I would murder me.
Mm-hm.
I almost feel like Jack
is mad at me.
He's disappointed in himself
that he changed his vote.
I get it. You know. I could have
changed my vote to Rachel
and Rachel could have gone.
and she could have been a Faithful.
and then I'd still be upset
because I got it wrong again.
- And you just don't know.
- I know.
It's hard to vote for your friend.
I really don't think
Jack is a Traitor.
I think he was genuinely upset
when James was banished.
It's really difficult.
It was really hard
to re-evaluate my vote.
just because. you know. James
has been a big support for me.
He's never been suspicious of me.
But in the end of it.
I had to stick with my feelings
and vote for Rachel.
I think there are still two Traitors
left in this game.
and it's going to take everything
that we have to find them.
It's just reminded me
that this is a game.
SHE CHUCKLES
You can't help but laugh.
Like. it is absolutely brilliant.
CLOCK CHIMES
All right. See you later.
The castle clock
has struck midnight.
It's been an eventful evening.
The Faithful are off to bed.
The Traitors. well. they're off
to the Turret.
There isn't a murder. but there's
a lot of planning to be done.
# Soldiers marching on
# Survivors standing strong... #
I really put my neck on the line
to keep Rachel in the game.
And I told myself
from the very beginning.
I had to make it through
this experience as a Traitor
with my moral compass still intact.
But I need to start
putting myself first
and making sure that I have the best
chance of winning this game.
# At the edge of the world
# Soldiers. #
God! I thought it was curtains
for you.
Me too.
That was hard.
But I didn't come here
just to lie down and roll over.
I came here to fight my way
to the final.
And I had luck on my side.
but that's what I've done.
We need to be really. really aligned
tomorrow. Rachel -
- because if not...
- We're done.
- ..neither of us are going to get
to that money.
- No.
I appreciate that you didn't vote
for me.
And we've played as a team the whole
time. and that's helped our game.
Let me tell you now -
if I wanted to take the money. I
would have got rid of you tonight...
- I know.
- ..because I think
it would have only helped my game.
I'm on the ropes. but I'm not
going down without a fight.
Whatever you think we need to do
tomorrow. I'm very willing to do.
We are this close to the finish line
and I hope he has my back.
And if he doesn't. God help him.
because I would take him down.
- Please trust me.
- I do.
- Please do not turn on me tomorrow.
I have no other play.
so I'm putting every ounce of trust
in you. Stephen.
You know. I'm saying the right
things. but I just don't...
I don't know what to do tomorrow.
# We'll take it all. #
Goodbye. Turret!
# So it begins... #
Movin' On Up
by Primal Scream
# I'm movin' on up now
# Gettin' out of the darkness... #
After ten banishments
and seven murders.
only five players remain
in the game.
and it's time for the finalists
to return to the castle
for their last breakfast.
# My light shines on! #
On my own.
I'm in the final!
SHE LAUGHS
It's the best feeling ever.
It genuinely is the best feeling.
I've got here by the skin
of my teeth.
Oh. my stomach's in knots.
like butterflies!
I was so nervous
when I arrived to the castle.
And I doubted myself and thought.
"I don't know if I can do this."
From the tap on the shoulder
at the start...
You are officially a Traitor.
..I settled and I was loving it.
Rachel is in that confessional.
The whole Harriet
in the confessional box
scared the life out of me.
I thought. "I just want to go home!"
Fiona!
I am not a liar!
Fiona. when you tell a lie.
you're a liar.
You are a Traitor.
I have loved this experience.
And I will do whatever it takes
to get me to that fire pit.
- I will not write your name down.
It would be absolutely amazing
to win that money for me
and for my mum and the kids.
To be the first female Traitor
to win this game
would be something else. And I want
to take it home for the girls.
KNOCK ON DOOR
Come in!
Hello. hello. hello!
Hello. finalist!
You all right?
I'm buzzing to be in the final.
Never thought I'd make it.
Faraaz. Nice to meet you.
This experience has been
an absolute roller-coaster.
It's taught me a lot about myself.
It's taught me a lot about
meeting people
from all different walks of life.
- Genuinely. I hope I see yous all
tomorrow. yeah?
- Yeah.
I am proud of the way
that I've played this game.
I think it's good that everyone
understands that it is a game.
I've voiced my opinions
and I've always voiced them
with logic and reason behind it.
- I did feel like you got
quite defensive.
- Yeah. I did.
- I snapped at you and I'm sorry.
- No. no. It's fine. You can do it.
I'm not arsed. truth.
I was nervous at the start
to bring points up...
Could I start. please?
..but once I got that off my chest.
I knew I was capable
of doing anything in this game.
Winning The Traitors
would mean so much.
No way!
I honestly love my mum and dad. and
that money would mean a lot to me
because of the experiences
that it would be able to unlock
for me and my family.
It would be unbelievable.
It's weird that
you don't have to say.
"I wonder who's not going
to come back..."
I know. when you know
everyone's coming.
KNOCK ON DOOR
Come in.
- Hello!
- Hi!
- Good morning.
- Good morning! How are you both?
- Good. How are you?
- Good.
- Oh. gosh.
So exciting! I'm in the final.
- My hands are getting sweaty.
- Yeah!
I don't really know
how I'm still here.
Please go into the castle.
CHEERING
From the start.
everyone had their doubts about me.
People have pointed fingers
at the way that I looked
after the Traitors pick.
- You just looked...scared.
- I cannot control how my body reacts.
My gut instinct is that
you are a Traitor.
For someone to have gone through so
much and. like. defended themselves
every single day at the Round Table.
it kind of then made me start
doubting myself a little bit.
I found a Shield token!
But my self-belief
has definitely developed
and I love the friendships
and the connections I've formed.
You're one of the people
that I'm most proud of in here.
I'm going to start crying.
Don't!
It's been wonderful.
Just the next step is to win.
KNOCK ON DOOR
Come in!
- Good morning!
- Morning.
We made it!
HE LAUGHS
Somebody's very happy.
I can't believe we made it.
Darling...
I can't believe I'm here!
When Claudia tapped my shoulder. my
heart was beating out of my chest.
I feel like the first half
of this experience.
I was an emotional wreck.
Just can't get my head around
how you've come back today.
to be honest.
But I've grown in confidence
and I'm super proud of myself.
I have been embroiled
in many controversies.
- Who do you think the Traitor
in the box is?
- Stephen.
The Caged Nine. The Library Five.
Why are we not looking at
who was in that room?
HE SCREAMS
For the first time.
I really feel like
the odds are stacked in my favour.
- We could take the Celtic connection
right to the end.
- I know!
Rachel and I made a promise
to each other
that we would never write each
other's names down on our slates.
but at this point now. I have
to think of myself as an individual.
It's not an easy decision.
I don't know what to do.
I really hope our last mission
doesn't involve any running.
I won't...
You'll have to carry me across.
Piggyback.
KNOCK ON DOOR
Come in!
Hello!
LAUGHTER
We're in the final!
Hello. everyone!
Oh. my God!
I'm part of the final five.
We're smashing it. guys!
To get to the final
and not have a single vote.
I'm happy with that.
I've just been me.
and I've just been open and honest.
I'm the sort of player
that wears his heart on his sleeve.
And I think that is a big reason as
to why I've got so far in this game.
Reece. I'm just going to
stick with my guts.
Although I've made my fair share
of mistakes...
I was 50-50 between the two of you.
I'm sorry. James.
..I'm not going to
get it wrong tonight.
THEY CHEER
I've got over
that little emotional blip.
And now I see with so much clarity
that Rachel is the Traitor.
I'm just going with my gut.
I have so much belief
that I can do it.
I can carry myself through.
take home the money.
I can't stop believing.
And us Faithfuls.
we're going to be victorious.
- I mean. it's been hard to see
a lot of people go.
- Yeah.
But I think James is my friend
- and I'm doing this for James now
as well.
- Aw!
- Good. good. good.
But we're in the final.
though. How amazing!
- I mean...
- You guys.
you've all done so well.
Likewise.
- Players.
- Good morning!
- Good morning. finalists!
- Yeah!
- So good!
Last day in the castle.
your last-ever breakfast here.
By the end of today.
we are going to find out
who's walking away
with the prize fund.
and it currently stands at £76.750.
But before that. you have
the mission of all missions.
And I'm going to be honest.
it's going to be tough.
I'm very pleased
I'm not on your boat.
I'll see you at the mission.
and congratulations.
- Thank you!
- Thank you. Claud!
- Oh. are we getting wet again?
LAUGHTER
This morning.
I need to plant seeds.
Rachel is up against the ropes
after that Round Table last night.
I cannot make myself
look more suspicious
by not putting her name out there.
I'm going to make a cup of tea.
Jade. and then go outside.
if you want to come for a wee walk.
- OK. we can...
- We need to go out and speak.
But quickly.
before we get tagalongs.
- What you saying. cuz?
- I wanted to
get you on your own.
- Yeah.
I wanted to tell you something
very important.
- Yeah.
- And this doesn't leave
this room.
After last night's Round Table.
Faraaz told me he thinks
he made a mistake.
And he thinks my reaction told him
that it wasn't me.
So all I've done is lean into that.
I might be on the ropes. but
I'm not going down without a fight.
What's one last lie between friends?
I know about body language
and microexpressions
and I have known who a Traitor was
from the very first night.
and I have hid behind them
to try and get to the final.
And when they turned on me
last night.
I thought I might as well
spill my guts.
So. it's Jade.
I have known from the start.
Her demeanour at the table
and her body language.
she clenches here on this side.
which I can see
every night she talks.
- Oh. I see that. I see that.
- I don't trust those three.
- Yeah.
- I do not trust those three.
If she gets into the final.
you've lost.
I was literally thinking of
saying that. this morning.
- it was Jade and Stephen for me.
- Yeah. I think so too.
They've just been doing it...
They've been inseparable
the past few days.
I was going to vote Jade first
and then vote Stephen after.
- Right. think... It's a number game.
- Yeah.
- If Jade goes...
- Mm-hm.
- ..that leaves in one Traitor.
- Yeah.
- And I would be more inclined
to go with Stephen.
- Yeah.
With Rachel. I don't know
if she's someone I can trust.
but she makes quite a lot of sense
with what she says.
It is well-thought-out.
You know after
the Round Table finished.
I was the first to stand
and walk out. right?
You know James.
how he went. "Tr-..."?
- I jolted my chair back.
- I jumped up.
- I jumped out of the seat.
The two of them next to me
did not flinch.
- What?!
- I was out of my seat.
- Can I...?
Can I share my post-cry clarity?
- Cos...
- Yeah.
- ..it's fresh
in my mind. but I'm trusting
- that you guys won't share it
with them.
- Mm-mm.
Well. first and foremost. obviously.
I can't keep going over it
in my head now. I made the mistake
of changing my vote
because I was more convinced
by Rachel's final plea than James's.
- Yeah.
- Before the Round Table. I felt
energy off her that was different.
It's the first time I've seen Rachel
acting in a way that looked nervous.
- Yeah.
- And she's such
a confident player.
I'm almost certain it's Rachel.
- I've told Faraaz about my suspicions
of Jade.
- Yeah.
No.
Mm-hm.
Uh-huh.
I know. I know. I know.
Yeah. yeah. yeah.
- After you!
- Thanks. mate.
The prize fund currently stands
at £76.750.
Today's final mission
is the last chance
for the players to work together
to add to the pot.
How do we feel about it being
the final day?
It feels like the full experience
from mission one to now.
You've done it all.
We do really work well as a team.
In the missions. yeah. we do.
At the Round Table. we don't.
But at the missions. we do!
Claudia always likes to go out
with a bang. doesn't she?
- It's going to be like
Mission: Impossible.
- Yeah.
Oh. Faraaz. it looks cold.
- Oh. my goodness.
- Oh. there's Claudia.
Oh. there she is!
- Hi!
- Hi.
I honestly can't believe that
I've made it to the final mission.
It is just like
this surreal experience.
Am I actually here?
My final five.
welcome to your final mission.
We've brought you into the heart
of the beautiful Highlands.
On that stunning loch is £10.000.
Pretty soon. you'll split into
two groups
and get into those two speedboats.
You have 45 minutes
to cross the loch.
gathering the money.
To help you find it. green flares
will signal the gold's location.
but if the flare turns red
before you reach the location.
I'm afraid it means you're too late.
You'll lose that gold forever.
Once you have attempted
to collect all the gold.
you just go to the end of the loch.
round that headland.
and you bring it to me.
And there. you will also
find your ride home.
No!
Oh. my God!
SHOUTING
SCREAMING
I've got a helicopter
flying over my head.
I've got boats on a loch.
thousands of pounds.
The whole situation feels like
some sort of. like.
hilarious fever dream.
And I love it.
Good luck.
Your 45 minutes starts...now!
HORN BLOWS
- OK. let's go. let's go. let's go.
- Go. go. go!
Go. go. go. go. go. go. go!
What they don't know is
they're going to meet me
at the top of an enormous dam.
And it is a very long way down
to their ride home.
This? This is just the starter.
That's it!
So I'm going to the middle. right?
OK!
LAUGHTER
- I'm going to go over there
somewhere.
- Over here?
- Yeah.
- Sorry about the...
LAUGHTER
I know. I know! I'm sorry!
Around the loch
were different pontoons.
We had to wait to see a flare
of green smoke.
- Green there!
- Go. go. go. go!
Jade. we're going for
the green smoke now.
You guys get into the middle.
And we then had to get over
to that pontoon...
Right. keep going. keep going.
..grab the money in time
or we got absolutely nothing.
- Got it. got it.
- That's two grand we've got.
They've got to the first pontoon.
They've retrieved the gold.
Oh. did they not get there?
No. look. yous go to that one.
We need to stay here.
We're on our way.
- There's green!
- Shit!
- Can you guys make that one?
- Yeah.
yeah. we're going to go for it.
We're going to go for it.
If they don't want to leave
any money floating out there
on the loch. I suggest
they move fast.
Why's our boat so slow?!
We're being taken by the waves.
I'll do what I can.
- Oh. it's red.
- Oh. what?
We missed it. It's red.
Sorry. guys.
- Go. go. go. go. go. go!
- Keep going.
keep going. keep going. keep going!
- Well done.
- Go back. go back. go back!
It's there. One there. one there.
to the right. to the right.
Just something about racing it
across the loch with the wind.
We were so full of adrenaline
to make sure
that we could get to
the green flares on time.
- OK. OK.
- You ready?
Yeah? You got it?
- Got it.
- Yes! Oh. yeah!
You've gone to all of the pontoons!
Come to me!
- Find me!
- Claudia. where are you?
- What. there?
That's not Claudia. like. there.
is it?
Hey!
We see you!
- Hang on! What?
- What is going on?
- We're climbing that ladder?
- Yeah. the ladder.
Shut up!
- Oh. my God!
- Whoa!
Oh. my God! No!
LAUGHTER
- Is that the ladder?!
- Yeah!
Are you all right going first. Jade?
We had to climb a ladder up the dam.
which was so high.
What?! It moves so much!
Oh. my God.
I guess the most important thing is.
don't look down.
Jade! Yes!
JADE SCREAMS
The most uncomfortable part
is the wedgie that I have right now.
It was so uncomfortable.
the worst wedgie I've ever had
in my life!
Oh. my God!
What am I doing?!
Let's go. Stephen!
Oh. my God! Oh!
Oh. my God. it's so high!
Whoa!
Oh... Oh. my legs are like jelly.
Come on. Grandma.
It's very. very different
when you have a genuine fear.
I don't really like heights.
- Keep going. Rachel!
- I'm not afraid of heights.
I can do this.
I'm not afraid of heights.
I didn't look down once.
because if I had've looked down
once. it was game over.
There's only five minutes left.
Come on!
They're almost there. almost there.
almost there.
- Yes!
- Come on. Rachel!
- Come on!
Yes. Rachel!
Come on!
I'm not the best with heights.
And my legs are starting to go
a bit wobbly.
There was a lot of nervous energy
going through me then.
Well done. We need Faraaz.
Otherwise. this money is not banked.
Come on. Faraaz!
SHOUTING
- Faraaz. come on. Come on!
- Quick. quick. quick!
- Hurry up!
- Come on. Faraaz!
THEY SHOUT
THEY CHEER
Well done!
Players. you did that
so brilliantly.
And you have added £9.000
to the prize fund.
Well done!
Let me just tell you this -
I'm going to give you the chance
to add another £10.000
to the prize fund.
All you have to do is get
to your ride. that helicopter.
in five minutes.
That's all you have to do.
Here's the tricky bit.
The only way to get
to that helicopter
- is to step off...
- Oh!
- ..this edge.
You will be running down the dam.
facing forward.
No! No. No.
- Are you serious?
- I'm deadly serious. Rachel.
OK. enormous luck.
Go get yourselves ready.
My knees started to go.
and I thought.
"I'm either going to vomit.
I'm going to faint.
"or I'm just going to refuse
to do this."
You all right?
You're not all right. OK.
So you three are on this ledge.
The other two are on
a different ledge.
- This is ridiculous.
- This is insane.
I honestly thought my knees
were going to go from under me.
Don't look.
Everything starts to
come into focus.
and you start seeing
how high up you are.
For the team and to bank that money.
I knew I had to do it.
Oh. this feels so weird!
No. no. no. This is too much.
This is too high.
- Good luck. Jade.
- Yeah!
HE LAUGHS
Players. your five minutes starts.
Three. two. one...
HORN BLOWS
Oh. geez!
Whoa!
- Whoa!
- Oh. my God!
It petrified me.
Oh. my God!
But at that point.
there's only one way to go.
I had to go down.
- That's it. Rach!
- Whee!
- Wait. Jade. you're doing it better
than me.
- Woo!
Faraaz. you're OK.
You can do it.
- Bloody hell!
- Faraaz. well done.
Oh...
SHE SCREAMS
HE GROANS
You're doing good. Rachel!
THEY LAUGH
JACK LAUGHS
Jade. how insane is this?
JADE LAUGHS
I just saw Rachel sprint
in front of me.
I mean. she was a machine.
Jade's at the bottom.
Jack is at the bottom!
What? What is going on here?
You have got this!
You're amazing!
Done it!
- Well done. Rachel!
- Oh!
Let's go. Stephen!
Yes! Well done!
- Come on. Faraaz!
- Yeah. yeah!
Well done!
- Guys. we've got to get to
the helicopter. Come on!
- Hug later!
Hug later! Helicopter first.
hug later.
- Here.
- Go on!
- They did it!
- That was unbelievable.
And I'm really. really proud
that I pushed myself to do it.
Oh...
THEY LAUGH
Come on! Yes!
Bye. Claudia!
Oh. my gosh!
Whew!
SHE LAUGHS
# Blue sky smiling at me... #
- Wow. look at this!
- Wow!
- This is ridiculous!
- Unreal!
I just had
the most amazing time today.
and I don't want to taint it
thinking about
the horrible Round Table
that's coming up tonight!
HE GROANS
THEY SCREAM. LAUGH
Oh. my God!
Is this not the best mission ever?
- Oh. yeah.
- Yeah.
Guys. 19 grand.
- What's our pot. like 95K
or something?
- Yeah.
It's a lot of dough.
I don't think money is
a motivating factor for Stephen.
but did that huge amount
that we won today make him think.
"I can do all of this on my own"?
The castle!
- Oh. my goodness me!
- That's stunning.
I know exactly what I need to do
tonight to win this game.
Stephen knows what he needs to do.
It's whether or not
he can hold his nerve
and that money
doesn't turn his head.
We just came out
of a helicopter!
Oh. my God!
I just... I can't stop thinking
about that moment
when you and I looked at each other
and we both had one hand on the bar.
"Come on. you go first!"
THEY LAUGH
Oh. that was nuts. wasn't it?
- My legs are still like jelly.
- Yeah. mine too!
- But what an experience. though.
- Oh!
How are you feeling
coming into the...? I don't know.
I think I know who I'm going to...
..yeah. I'm going to go for
on the Round Table.
There's a common theme
where Traitors try and almost like
guilt-trip people before they go.
Yeah. she got very defensive
about it.
And it worked for me
cos I changed my mind.
You know. Faraaz hasn't voted
for a single Traitor.
- He hasn't voted for Hugo.
- Not for Fiona either.
He didn't vote for Fiona.
I didn't notice that.
Did he vote for Rachel
at the last one?
Yeah. but then
after the Round Table.
he was like. "Oh. yeah.
I'm really sorry I voted for you."
- I was like...
- Yeah. he told me he
changed his mind...
.."Are you backing down?"
- Mmm.
- Like. you've come after me
with such conviction.
you went after Sam
- Like...
- Why has he suddenly changed
his mind?
- Do you know what I mean?
I think Faraaz being able
to coast through the game.
not voted out a Traitor.
and to be able to stay so calm
and collected at the Round Table.
I think it's because you know
that you've got the majority
of the power.
and I think that's
because he's a Traitor.
Just to go into the library
and have a wee read.
Last night was just so brutal.
Well. it mightn't mean an awful lot.
but I really appreciated your vote.
And going into tonight.
I've already said it to Faraaz -
I'm not saying who I'm voting for.
I'm... For the first time.
I'm going to hold my cards
- close to my chest...
- That's fair enough. yeah.
..because I felt so
vulnerable last night.
- Can I join in on...?
- Yeah.
- You can. of course.
- You all right. man?
- Yeah. sport.
Y'all right?
- Yeah.
- Am I all right to talk to Jack
for a bit? Is that all right?
- Sure.
I'm leaning really. really heavily
on Faraaz to get Jade out.
so any conversation in private
just makes me feel nervous.
This doesn't leave this room. right?
It's a game of numbers.
We need to vote Jade first. then
I'll go with you and vote Rachel
and then we vote Stephen
and we win it together.
Cos I just want to be stood
there with you at the end.
I don't think Rachel is a Traitor.
but I'm not 100% convinced with it.
I'm 99. and 99 is not enough.
So the only person I do trust
100% in this game is Jack.
See. my plan was that I was
going to vote Rachel first.
No. vote... I'm telling you.
because Rachel's voting Jade first.
How do you know
who she's going to vote for?
She told me in confidence
because she trusts me.
So she's just lied to my face.
I'm convinced. 100%
convinced it is Rachel.
That aside. I don't know
who I can really trust fully.
Me and Jack were just
talking about Rachel
at last night's round table.
She was. like. basically
guilt-tripping.
The way that James
presented himself at the end
was just someone that had
absolutely nothing to prove.
And then I'm wondering if.
because her defence was
so articulate and thought out.
is that actually what it was. like.
- thought out...?
- And rehearsed.
I think. like. that's something
that has been playing on my mind
a lot. and round the table
tonight I just don't know
if I can carry on with that
still in the game.
You know? Because that's going to
make me really. really anxious.
- It's going to bug me.
- Yeah.
Defending Rachel could actually
spell the end of my game.
because right now I would
say she's probably
the one with the most heat
on her in the castle.
And if I don't vote for her
at the Round Table tonight.
I think both Jack and Jade
will think it's really suspicious.
I feel like. you know. we've
established trust in each other.
- I'm a Faithful. and I know it's
the same with you.
- Yeah.
If I get to the end of this game and
the person that I'm there with.
- like. turns around and tells me that
they are a Traitor...
- Yeah.
- ..it's devastating.
At this point. like.
I just need to go with my gut.
# Are you. are you
Coming to the tree?
# Strange things did happen here
No stranger would it be
# If we met at midnight
in the hanging tree. #
We started with 22 players
and now only five remain.
They are about to head into
their final Round Table.
where they will banish
for the last time.
Every move that they've made
has led up to this.
There is no room for mistakes.
The plan at this point is that
myself. Stephen and Faraaz
vote for Jade.
I just hope they stick to the plan.
We have to get a Traitor out.
But it's so hard to decipher between
who is being honest with me
and who is lying to my face.
Oh. God. I'm going to
kick myself if I'm wrong!
This last Round Table
means everything.
Jack is the only person I trust.
My game plan is
get Jade out first.
then vote Rachel and Stephen. and me
and Jack win together as Faithfuls.
Going into this Round Table.
I have people that I trust.
and that would be Jack and Stephen.
So I know I've got people
in my corner to defend me.
but I don't know how it will go.
I am surrounded by people that
are putting their trust in me.
Right now. I'm so torn
over which way to go.
I need to make a decision
between my fellow Traitor
that I've been with from
the very beginning.
and my best friends in this castle.
HE HEAVES A SIGH
Players. welcome to your
final Round Table.
You were excellent
in today's mission
and added £19.000 to the pot.
Your final prize fund
is a staggering
£95.750.
Please remember - at the end.
if only Faithful remain.
they share the money.
But if there is still a
Traitor here. they take it all.
Also. banished players will
no longer reveal their
true identities as they leave.
So from now on. you are relying
only on gut feelings and instinct.
So I want to ask you this -
who do you want to
end the game with?
Who do you want to
share the money with?
Who do you believe is a Faithful.
and who do you suspect is a Traitor?
For the final time. then.
players. the floor is yours.
I'd like to start.
Jade. it's probably no surprise.
With Amanda and her experience.
she was like a dog with
a bone with you.
Like. she was. like. really adamant.
So I feel as if that's something
that sort of sat in my mind.
But she was adamant on. like.
the way that I looked
at the first Round Table.
That in itself has. like.
been the only. like. real thing.
To have one line of evidence.
I can't even control it.
do you know what I mean?
Like. I was hot.
the room was full.
So I think she was just
so focused on you.
and I think that sort of just tells
a bit of a story to me anyway.
You can make a story out of it
if you want. but it's untrue.
- That's all I'm...
- OK.
- Yeah.
And then just moving on from that.
I feel as if in a way
you got rid of everyone
who was pointing towards you
in quite a way that went unnoticed.
OK. well. with that regard.
I'm being set up.
Like. if I was a Traitor. would I
leave that kind of paper trail?
Is there anything with my behaviours
or anything that I've done
around all the circumstantial
stuff that's happened around me
that would suggest
that I'm a Traitor?
No. but I feel.
as I've just laid out...
- Well. there you go - "no".
- I've just...
I've just laid out a lot of things
that I feel are quite Traitorous...
- That I've had no control over.
- ..and that cast suspicions with me.
Obviously. you would say that.
you know what I mean?
- But obviously you'd come at me...
- You would say that.
- ..but I think you're a Traitor...
- Yeah. that's fine.
..so then you've set that up.
I don't know if you guys remember.
but as James was making
his reveal last night.
he went. "I am a Tr..."
and I was literally on
the edge of my seat.
- And. like. you didn't budge.
- Well. that's a lie.
That is... You've genuinely
just barefaced lied
cos I literally went like that.
- And I know I did.
- But you just seemed. like. chill.
No. no. I wasn't. That's wrong.
And also. to talk
about voting patterns -
as far as I'm aware.
you're the only person sat
at this table who's not
voted out a Traitor.
Yeah. no. I haven't.
- Why?
- Cos I didn't think Hugo
and Fiona were Traitors.
That's just me not seeing that.
Erm. given how last night went.
I feel like I need to talk.
So I want to remind you
of a couple of facts
that you might have forgotten
about throughout the game.
If you look at Amanda.
Amanda was my closest friend
in the whole castle...
..and she was a detective who
questioned people for a living.
who sought out liars
and interrogated people.
And not once did she suspect me of
anything. because I've never lied.
You look at Fiona. and I was
instrumental in getting Fiona out.
And I've heard the whispers.
It wasn't Traitor on Traitor.
It was the fact that I
caught her out in a lie.
And lastly. I am an
intelligent woman.
If I was a Traitor. would I be
sitting here with no allies?
I have no-one for a backup vote.
If I was a Traitor. I would have
taken somebody else along.
I would have made sure I
got them to the final.
because at this point in time.
I'm OK with the fact
that I'll probably not
win this game.
- Can I ask you a question. Rachel?
- Fire away.
There was a moment yesterday
when you made the point
about you got a Traitor out.
and you're proud of that.
and "don't put me down. because
that's my achievement" and stuff.
I says. "Don't take it
away from me."
"Don't take it away" from you.
If you are a Faithful - and I feel
terrible even asking this -
but if you're not. and it was a way
to make everyone feel guilty.
and maybe as an attempt
to change people's minds
- at the last minute...
- No.
- ..it worked for me
cos it was part of the reason
why I changed my mind.
I. yeah. I don't need to
make people feel guilty.
I am so competitive
and I don't really care
what happens going forward.
But don't let - I was just saying -
don't take away the one thing
that I know I've done.
So. no. it wasn't meant
to make anyone feel guilty.
I don't want to get through a game.
like. playing on people's emotions.
Right.
Going back to last night.
Faraaz and Rachel were standing
at the bar and...
..the mood
in that bar was completely different
to the mood outside of that bar.
I felt that from myself.
Jade and Jack.
and I'm not trying
to defend people here.
but we were stressed.
we were annoyed.
we were upset because not only did
we get a Faithful out.
who was James. we also wasted
our last identity reveal
- on a Faithful.
- So what was the mood
like in the bar?
You were grinning like
a Cheshire cat.
I was... I was laughing that it came
down to chance
that I actually was still here
from a chest
that I didn't feel a Shield was in.
So. to me. I just was sitting
shaking my head.
going. "I can't believe this.
This is not how I wanted it to be."
I was totally thinking about myself.
I am unbelievably proud
of myself coming into this game
and playing this game with
so much integrity.
and I am so proud that my kids get
to watch me playing this game
faithful to the team.
So I just want to remind you.
just look up and look out.
and sometimes it's the people
that you're closest to.
Players. the time for talk is over.
You now need to vote for the person
you believe is a Traitor.
Has everyone voted?
Then the votes are locked in.
Jack. we will start with you.
Who do you believe is a Traitor
and why?
HE CLEARS THROAT
So. I obviously changed my mind
last night
and I keep kicking myself for it.
Erm...
Rachel. I've voted for you.
And. as always.
I'm sorry if I'm wrong.
but I'm just...
Yeah.
I'm going to stick with it tonight.
Rachel. who do you believe
is a Traitor and why?
I voted for Jade.
At this point in the game.
I trust Amanda over anybody else
at this table.
Jade?
Faraaz. I voted for yourself.
I think you're trying to spin
a lot of what's going on around me
and paint it
in a particular kind of light.
I think the Traitors are setting me
up to be an easy banishment
and I think that's exactly
what's going on here.
Faraaz. who do you believe
is a Traitor and why?
For reasons aforementioned.
I voted for yourself. Jade.
So a vote count - two for Jade.
one for Rachel and one for Faraaz.
It all comes down to this last vote.
If Stephen votes for either
Jade or Jack.
then Jade has been banished.
If Stephen has voted
for either Rachel or Faraaz.
we have a draw.
So for the final vote. Stephen.
who do you believe is a Traitor
and why?
HE EXHALES
I have let my heart dictate
pretty much everything I've done
at this table.
And tonight I have to think
with my head.
And I cannot stand at that fire pit
if I have suspicions on anyone.
Jade. I'm so sorry. my darling.
Jade.
you have been utterly brilliant.
You have received the most votes.
You have been banished from
the castle.
Please leave.
SHE SNIFFLES
SHE EXHALES
I thought I trusted Stephen.
Betrayal is really hard.
And I've spent my time
playing this game...
..like. blinded by trust.
So Jade has been banished.
but was she a Faithful
or was she a Traitor?
You will only find that out
when this game ends.
Players. I need you to think
about your next move very carefully.
because that will decide
your fate.
Later tonight.
you will face each other
at the Endgame.
Players. you are the final four.
I didn't see that coming.
I just felt like her arguments
tonight just weren't...
I think the thing
that kind of just swayed me
at the very end was when she said.
"You didn't budge
when James said. 'Tr-...'"
and you were very certain
of the fact that that was a lie.
Seeing how upset Jade was
when I voted for her
actually really broke me.
I feel so bad.
I couldn't sit at the Round Table
and vote for Rachel
if I didn't think she was
going to get enough votes
to get her out straight away.
And so I had to make
a split-second decision
and vote for Jade.
I now need to understand how
I'm going to play
this Endgame.
JACK SIGHS
There's so much tension
in the air right now.
HE SIGHS
The thing is. I've just
had this tiny little thought
in my mind that if Stephen's able
to remove Jade at this stage.
this person he's been
so close with the whole time.
he also has the ability to be
a Traitor.
No. I can't. You know what.
I just can't...
I can't think about that.
My mind's just running wild now.
Oh. God!
Oh!
- So I'm just holding on to that.
- I know.
I just hadn't realised how difficult
it was going to be voting.
A. for Jade.
but. B. then not even knowing
if I've made the right choice
or not.
Stephen. he's looking
a little bit guilty.
There's a little bit of nervousness.
I trust that
we have been a team
from the first night up until now.
so whether
or not he follows through...
I'm just hoping that he realises
that I would be
the harder person to answer to
if he goes back on a promise.
Tell you what.
I did not see him voting for her.
Do you think she started crying
because he turned on her
at the last minute?
He's like...
- And he has Jack in his pocket.
- Yeah. I know.
I'm going to vote for Stephen.
I am suspicious of Stephen.
and him voting for Jade only
solidified that suspicion.
Me and Jack
need to really stick together.
I feel as if we need to be smart
with our votes
and protect ourselves.
I'm still convinced by my theory.
I'm sticking with Rachel.
but before the Round Table.
Faraaz was pushing me
so hard to go against you...
..to make sure
that it was me and him at the end.
And it leaves. like.
the most impossible decision
of. like. you two.
Two people that I felt I trusted.
It's going to be absolutely
horrific
if you look at me
and say. "I'm a Traitor."
I'm not going to look at you
Mate. I'm not. I'm not going
to do you over like that.
There's a high chance
that Faraaz could really kind of
compete against me
to win Jack over.
but I really think he trusts me
as a Faithful over Faraaz.
I really do.
I have to put my trust
in someone.
The Endgame is fast approaching.
and we have two Faithful
and two Traitors.
So the question is.
will the Faithful stick together
and share the prize fund?
Or will the Traitors remain
undetected and take it all?
# I've learned to lose you.
can't afford to... #
- Final four.
- I know. yeah.
How much would you like to win?
I'd love to win.
I hope Jack stays with me
and us two sharing
that prize pot as Faithfuls.
Talk to me about the money.
- You wanted to take your family
on pilgrimage.
- Yeah.
Yeah. to win that money
and to be able to create
that experience with my family
would be absolutely unreal.
and now it's within
touching distance. it's...
Yeah. it's a surreal feeling.
# Call me friend but keep me
closer... #
So now we come to the Endgame.
Do you know what you're going to do?
My gut is telling me
to stick with Rachel for starters.
And then when it comes down to
Faraaz or Stephen...
..it's so. so difficult.
because I can't help
but feel like I've been
the obvious Faithful
that's been strung along
by a Traitor.
At the end. I just... Gosh. I hope
we're two Faithful standing there.
# Well. I could lie.
say I like it like that
# Like it like that... #
Talk to me about you and Stephen.
because we've never had that before.
I know. We made a promise and. like.
I really would like to win it
with him.
Whether or not that pact stays true
to the end. we'll see.
- but when I think back to
why I applied...
- Yeah.
..and the difference
that it could make for me
and my beautiful family...
Let's talk about your mum.
When you know her memories are going
and you have an opportunity
to help her create. like.
the nicest ones ever.
like. that is very precious.
- Yeah.
- So I'm going to win it.
if Stephen's head doesn't get turned
by the money.
# Well. I could lie.
say I like it like that
# Like it like that... #
How have you found it?
This is the toughest thing
I have ever done.
but I have had so much fun.
You're going into the Endgame.
What's your plan?
I see two paths through
this Endgame.
One is with Rachel.
One is without.
47.500 and something pounds
is better than nothing.
But 95.750 is so much more.
# I could lie.
say I like it like that
# Like it like that... #
Players...
..every move you have made
in the game has led to this.
This is where it ends.
Precisely when it ends.
well. that is up to you.
as you are now in control.
You have to ask yourselves.
are there any Traitors left
in your midst?
The answer to
that question is very important.
because it could be worth £95.750.
If you believe you are all Faithful
and you choose to end the game.
that money will be split
equally amongst you.
However.
if there are any Traitors remaining.
they take it all.
In front of each of you is a chest.
In there are ceremonial pouches.
One is labelled "banish again".
One is labelled "endgame".
If you believe there is still
a Traitor here.
choose banish again.
If you believe you are all
Faithful.
choose endgame.
If just one of you
chooses banish again.
all four of you will vote
a player out.
This game only ends when you choose
or when there
are two players remaining.
Please now choose your pouch.
Banish again or endgame.
I will now throw your pouches
into the fire.
Faraaz. we're about
to reveal your decision.
You have voted to banish again. Why?
I still think
there's a Traitor here.
So we will go to a vote.
but let's just see how
the rest of you voted.
Rachel.
You have voted to banish again. Why?
There's still a Traitor amongst us.
Jack. let's see
what you have chosen to do.
You have voted to banish again. Why?
I still feel there's a Traitor
here amongst us.
And lastly. Stephen. let's see
what you have chosen to do.
You have chosen to banish again.
Why?
Like the rest.
I'm still thinking
there's a Traitor here.
Players. the time has come to vote.
Please take the slate
in front of you
and write down the name
of the person
you wish to banish from the game.
Has everyone voted?
Yeah.
Faraaz.
we're going to start with you.
Who do you believe should
be banished and why?
I voted Stephen.
I've had my suspicions on him
for a while
and I feel as if his vote
for Jade was Traitor on Traitor.
Rachel?
I voted for Faraaz.
I think you tried
to sway my vote today.
And that's screaming Traitor to me.
Jack?
I'm sorry. Rachel.
I stuck with my vote from earlier.
So it all comes down
to this last vote.
Stephen?
Faraaz. pal. I'm really sorry.
I do believe you've been a Traitor
in this game from the beginning.
Faraaz. you have been excellent.
You have received the most votes.
You are banished from the castle.
Please leave.
To get that close
and to just miss out.
it's a hard pill to swallow.
but it's completely my fault.
I did think Stephen was a Traitor.
I think Rachel is a Faithful.
I think she just thought...
Oh. you know what?
It could be Rachel and Stephen.
Oh. yeah. Defo's Rachel and Stephen.
Idiot.
So. Faraaz has been banished
and only three of you remain.
Are you all Faithful.
or are there Traitors in this trio?
You can end things right here.
right now.
or you can banish once more.
This is your last chance
to banish someone.
as the game automatically ends
when there
are just two players remaining.
Please select your pouches.
STEPHEN EXHALES
Thank you.
Let's see
what you've all decided to do.
Jack. we're going to start with you.
Did you decide to end the game
or banish again?
Jack.
you've decided to banish again. Why?
I still feel like there may be
a Traitor here
and I just can't take the risk.
So Jack has chosen to banish again.
That means you will
definitely vote again.
Stephen. let's see
what you chose to do.
Stephen. you chose to banish again.
Why?
There's one person in particular
that I've seen myself
standing here with.
Rachel. let's see
what you chose to do.
You chose to banish again. Why?
I was tempted to end the game
and then I thought.
"I can't take the risk."
I think there's one still here.
Thank you.
Players. you all chose
to banish again.
So you will now banish
for the final time.
Please write down the name
of the person you wish to banish.
Remember. whatever happens.
the game automatically ends
after this.
Has everyone voted?
Rachel.
we're going to start with you.
Who have you voted to banish
and why?
I voted for Jack.
Simply because I trust Stephen more.
Jack. who do you believe should
be banished and why?
Rachel.
I've still stuck with the same vote.
And. as always.
I'm sorry if I'm wrong.
but I said it
and I'll say it again.
I think you'd make
a phenomenal Traitor.
Thank you.
So it all comes down
to this final vote.
Stephen. who do you believe
should be banished and why?
STEPHEN EXHALES
I came into this game...
..and I decided I was going
to play a fair and honest game.
And so. for reasons
that will become clear...
..Jack. I've written your name down.
Wow.
HE SCOFFS
Jack.
you have received the most votes.
You are banished from the game.
You have been truly excellent.
Please now leave the castle.
So frustrating.
That's completely unexpected.
Like. what a curveball.
I've been totally played.
Maybe they were both Traitors
and they agreed
that they'd win the game together.
Who knows?
HE SNIFFS
You did it.
Oh. my God.
You have each got £47.875.
Go on. cuddle each other.
Oh. my God!
Oh. my!
I thought when you weren't
looking me in the eye
that you'd just decided to change
your mind at the last minute.
I was just pulling your leg.
Don't do that!
STEPHEN LAUGHS
I'll be honest. I had moments
where I was doubting what
I was going to do tonight. but...
..I had...I couldn't go back on
my word to you.
It just wasn't worth the money
and I couldn't have walked out
of here by lying to you.
- Two Traitors. but totally
faithful to each other.
- Oh!
- Yeah.
- You did it.
You absolutely did it.
Congratulations.
- I'm so proud of you. honestly.
- I'm very proud of you.
- I'm so proud of you.
- Oh. I love you.
- Oh. I love you. too.
STEPHEN LAUGHS
I can't believe I've just won
The Traitors.
I'm just a wee boy from
the Isle of Lewis.
This kind of stuff doesn't really
happen to me.
This isn't the kind of money that me
and my family deal with. you know?
It's going to make such
a difference
and I just know they're going to be
so proud.
It's the best feeling in the world.
I really thought it was such
a big achievement
to be the first female Traitor
to make it to the final.
Oh. my goodness.
And then to win...
CORK POPS
THEY CHEER
I think it will be a very long time
until you get the smile off my face.
To the Traitors!
CLAUDIA SCREAMS
I've been dying to say that.
I'm really looking forward
to not having to lie.
That's a lot. That's a lot of lying.
So I'm looking forward
to just breathing
and just making the nicest
memories with my mum
that I will remember forever.
We are the Traitors!
THEY CHEER
- Yes!
- Come on!